bbm.com 2018-12-29

# BBM Privacy Policy

Hello, BBM community! 

We are on a mission to provide exciting new services for the BBM community and have made a number of exciting updates over the last year. As part of our continuing efforts to enhance our Services, we have updated our BBM Terms (e.g., Privacy Policy, Terms of Service, Channel and Official Account Terms and Community Guidelines for all BBM users and providers of Services). 

For the optimal BBM experience, please provide accurate, complete and true information about yourself to us and keep your information updated. Click [here](https://help.bbm.com/en/support/solutions/articles/19000073751-change-your-account-settings) to update your personal information. This is very important, especially when you change your device, phone or phone number! Please take the necessary security measures to safeguard the data in your phone and device! 

All views are welcome but please comply with our community guidelines and applicable laws. BBM should not be used for any abusive, derogatory, offensive, pornographic, defamatory, unauthorized or unlawful purpose. 

If you reside in the EU/EEA, you may elect to instruct us not to collect any personal information about you by emailing [support@bbmtek.com](mailto:support@bbmtek.com). 

When we or our partners enhance our Services or release exciting products and services we may update you via SMS, e-mail and/or in-app notifications in BBM so that you can stay connected within the BBM community. 

If you have any concerns regarding our updated BBM Terms, please email us at [support@bbmtek.com](mailto:support@bbmtek.com). BBM is brought to you by Creative Media Works (CMW), used under licence from BlackBerry Limited. 

As part of our continuing efforts to protect your privacy, we have updated our Privacy Policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) which you accept upon opening your BBM user account or visiting our website, or using or providing of any of the Services. 

This Privacy Policy describes how CMW Group collect, use, process, transfer, disclose and protect your personal data or information (e.g., which may identify you or another individual) (“ **Personal Information** ”) that you may provide from time to time, through the Services or any other communications with CMW Group. Any capitalized terms in this Privacy Policy that are not defined herein have the meaning set out in the BBM Terms of Service. 

This Privacy Policy and other relevant agreements and notices associated with certain Services ( **“Notice”** ) are subject to all applicable personal data protection laws including legislation, regulations and the orders of any courts or other lawful authorities, other lawful requests or legal processes (“ **Data Laws** ”). 

* **CMW GROUP’S RESPONSIBILITY**

Creative Media Works Pte. Ltd. (Company Registration No. 201609444E) and its related corporations and affiliates (“ **CMW Group** ”) seek to properly handle and manage your Personal Information that it collects, uses, discloses, stores, processes and transfers for the provision of Services ( **“Use”** ), in accordance with Data Laws and this Privacy Policy. 

* **YOUR CONSENT** By the following conduct: 

  1. using CMW Group’s Services (including the installation and/or use of software, or associated Internet service or mobile data service, or the creation of a User ID or other user account); 

  2. corresponding with CMW Group; 

  3. entering a contest sponsored by CMW Group; or 

  4. otherwise interacting with CMW Group; 

you consent to CMW Group, their service providers and other third parties’ Use of your Personal Information or information under this Privacy Policy and agree to BBM Terms of Service. 

By submitting or otherwise making available Personal Information relating to other individuals (such as your spouse, family members, employees or any other third parties, including minors), you represent that you are authorized to provide such information to CMW Group and that you have obtained their explicit prior consent to CMW Group’s Use in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Before using any of the Services, you may be required to agree to an applicable Notice that may contain additional information regarding the Use by CMW Group, their service providers, and other third parties. Your use of the Services thereafter confirms your agreement to such Notice and your consent for your Personal Data to be Used by CMW Group, their service providers and other third parties (as the case may be) to collect, use, process and disclose for the purposes identified in such Notice. 

  1. In certain circumstances, your Personal Information may be Used without your consent depending on the jurisdiction and any other applicable laws. For example, CMW Group may not seek consent for its Use: 

    1. in the case of an emergency that threatens the life, health or safety of an individual; 

    2. when necessary for a purpose that is clearly in your interest, if consent cannot be obtained in a timely way; 

    3. when necessary for any investigation; 

    4. when disclosure is necessary to obtain legal services; 

    5. to recover a debt; 

    6. when necessary for proceedings including a subpoena, warrant or other court order, lawful or enforcement request or legal process; or 

    7. as may be otherwise required or permitted by law. 

  2. **Children’s Personal Information**

CMW Group does not knowingly Use Personal Information from individuals under the age of 13 without the consent of their parent or legal guardian. If you are under the age of 13 or a minor, please do not submit any Personal Information through our Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this Privacy Policy by instructing their children never to provide Personal Information through our Services without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 or a minor has provided Personal Information to us through our Services, please contact us at [dpo@bbmtek.com](mailto:dpo@bbmtek.com) and we will endeavour to delete that information and terminate the minor’s account from our databases. 

  3. **Aggregated or Anonymous Information**

CMW Group may process, sell, trade or rent anonymous information that is not associated with or linked to an identifiable individual. 

* **INFORMATION THAT CMW GROUP COLLECTS**

Depending on the extent of the Services used and the nature of your interaction with CMW Group, CMW Group may collect the following Personal Information from you: 

  1. **Account and Membership Information:** Information processed could include your name, postal address, email address, telephone number, User ID, device identifier information such as your BBM PIN, custom BBM PIN, airtime service provider information, information contained in communications with CMW Group and any recorded complaints. CMW Group may also process your account credentials, passwords, profile information, language preference, country and time zone, and other information you provide to facilitate the Services you use. 

  2. **Profile Management:** CMW Group may use your Personal Information such as user account information (which may include your User ID) and information about products and services that are associated with your user account to better understand, analyse and predict your preferences and interests, and may combine it with other information to customize your experience, suggest other products and services to you, and provide you with more relevant promotional content based on your user profile. **This does not mean that data that personally identifies you will be shared with third party advertisers**. CMW Group and their service providers may use, collect, disclose and process advertising identifiers, including those provided by other software platforms, or similar identifier, in order to facilitate CMW Group in conducting analytics or providing promotional content or other information that may be relevant to you, and CMW Group may connect such identifiers with your user profile. 

  3. **Third Party Offerings:** In some cases, CMW Group may process information about applications used on your device including “ **Third Party Offerings** ” (i.e. applications, products, services, software, websites or content provided by a third party, including an airtime service provider or application developer, that may be used in conjunction with Services, but are not offered, operated or supported by CMW Group). If you choose to use Third Party Offerings with your user account with CMW Group, certain information may be collected and disclosed to the third party, or from the third party to CMW Group, in order to facilitate or improve the services and functionality provided. 

  4. **Social Functionality:** The Services include a " **social functionality** " element that allows you to make yourself discoverable and connect with other individuals, and to improve or enhance your experience with the Services or other services, software or content that are integrated with the Services. In order to provide such functionality, you agree that your availability to interact or connect with the others may be indicated to other users, and your profile, display names, display pictures, status messages, membership status, and other identifiers or information may be viewed and, in some cases, commented on by other users. For example, if you elect to use your user account credentials with ID Accessible Services, you agree that, where such functionality exists: (i) your BBM Contacts may see whether you are using such Service; (ii) your BBM Contacts may see your profile for the service and the software and content (such as games, music or other media files, depending on the Service or software) that you have downloaded, are consuming, or that is available for sharing as part of your use of the service, as well as comments you or others make about the Service, software and content; (iii) when you submit comments about your BBM Contacts or the software or content such BBM Contacts have downloaded or are consuming as part of their use of the Service, information about you (such as your comments, user profile name, and display picture) may be displayed to other contacts of that BBM Contact, and (iv) the Service may include an automated functionality that performs analysis to develop recommendations based on your preferences and utilization of the service, content or software. Please check the applicable settings options for the relevant ID Accessible Services for available options to connect to or disconnect from your user account with CMW Group and adjust any other available privacy settings for such Services or software. 

  5. **BBM Channels or Official Accounts**. By becoming a subscriber to a Channel or Official Account, you agree that certain information about you, including your display name, display picture and other information contained in your public profile, will be accessible by the Channel or Official Account administrator, and any Personal Information that is provided to the Channel or Official Account administrator will be subject to the applicable privacy policy of the Channel or Official Account administrator. CMW Group may also use information collected in connection with your use of BBM Channels or Official Accounts, including your Channel or Official Account subscriptions and activities, information associated to your user profile and user account, and your location, to understand and predict your preferences and interests in order to develop, communicate, or provide you with Channels or Official Accounts recommendations, content or services that may interest you. CMW Group may also combine such data with information about your use of other products and Services to customize your experience, suggest other products and services to you, and provide you with more relevant promotional content based on your user profile. This may include sending you invitations-to-subscribe, messages and posts on behalf of Channel or Official Account administrators who request us to send messages to BBM Channels or Official Accounts users or target audience segments that match your demographic profile and interests. However, we will not provide personally identifiable information to Channel or Official Account administrators unless you give us permission to do so (for example, as set out in this Privacy Policy). The Channel or Official Account administrators may send you content, offers, information about promotions, or other communications within the Services. Please review the applicable settings within the Portal for available controls regarding how to block future unsolicited invites or messages from a particular Channel or Official Account, and how to unsubscribe from a Channel or Official Account. 

  6. **Cloud-Based or Back-Up Data:** If you use a cloud-based (which include remote access or storage functionality) or back-up and restore service provided by or on behalf of CMW Group, information from your device or account including contacts, email addresses, calendar, reminder entries, photos, memo, tasks, display pictures, status, personal messages, address book information, media files and other on-device information may be sent to CMW Group in order to facilitate or improve the use, remote access and restoration of that data on your device through the service provided. 

  7. **Cookies or Similar Technologies:** A cookie is a small text file or piece of data that is downloaded to and stored on your computer or device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes the cookie. As part of the Services, CMW Group may use different types of cookies or similar technologies ( **“Cookies”** ) from time to time. Certain Cookies are **_necessary_** to facilitate your use of the Services (such as when you use a shopping basket) or to protect both you and CMW Group when you sign-in to certain services (such as storing your credentials to make it easier whenever you want to use the Services or to confirm that you are logged in). Other Cookies are more **_performance_** -related such as for analytics or contextual purposes to help CMW Group understand how users engage with the Services so CMW Group can provide new and enhanced Services (such as which pages or features are most popular). Some Cookies are more **_function_** -related and help personalize your experience and make the Services easier to use (such as your language or jurisdiction preferences), or to help CMW Group display personalized content to you. Other Cookies or similar technologies may be used for **_targeted advertising_** purposes (e.g. certain Services may be supported by advertising revenue and display advertisements and promotions which may be targeted against non-personally identifiable attributes or aggregate data collected by CMW Group, and CMW Group or their service providers may place such advertising on the Services). Anonymized information about usage of the Services may be provided in a form that does not personally identify you to the service providers of CMW Group as part of analytics services and to help manage online advertising. You consent to the collection of your Personal Information using Cookies for the purposes set out in this paragraph. You may withdraw your consent to the collection of your Personal Information using Cookies by disabling Cookies on your browser. Most browsers are initially set to accept Cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to refuse Cookies or to indicate when a Cookie is being sent. You can typically remove or block browser Cookies using the settings in your browser, but that may impact your ability to use certain Services as they may not work well or at all with Cookies disabled. Please visit the section below on “ **Managing your preferences** ” for more information on managing the use of Cookies by CMW Group. 

  8. **Financial Information:** If you use the Services for purchases or other financial transactions (such as when you make a purchase from CMW Group’s merchant partners), CMW Group and such partners collect information about the purchase or transaction. This includes payment information, such as your credit or debit card number and other card information; other account and authentication information; and billing, shipping and contact details. CMW Group may also process credit card or other payment information and use it to facilitate billing and credit services and conduct credit checks, as applicable. Similarly, CMW Group may process payment or other financial information when you use Near Field Communications functionality. 

  9. **General Usage Data:** In some cases, information like technical properties and general usage information of software and hardware utilized in conjunction with the Services including device or computer information (for example, device PIN, IMEI, IMSI, UDID, MAC address or similar identifiers, and device model) might be processed when you use such products, services or software (e.g. type of web browser, referring or exit web pages, operating system version, hardware model of your device or personal computer platform, IP address and information about Internet service or mobile data service providers). 

  10. **Location Information:** The Services or a portion thereof may provide functionality that relies upon location information associated to your device (e.g. Global Positioning System (GPS) or similar satellite triangulation information, carrier or tower ID, the BSSID (Broadcast Service Set Identifier) and MAC address (Media Access Control address) of Wi-Fi access points, and signal strength of visible Wi-Fi hotspots or wireless towers) location information associated to your device (“ **Location-based Services** ”). By using such Location-based Services, you acknowledge and agree that: (i) CMW Group or their service providers may collect, use, disclose and/or process such location information to provide you with or facilitate the provision of information and services (e.g. mapping services, measuring traffic congestion, location-sensitive promotions or coupons); and (ii) you assume responsibility for the risks involved in using such Location-based Services, and it is your responsibility to use them appropriately and according to applicable laws. If you are also a user of BBM Channels or Official Accounts, you acknowledge and agree that the Location-based Services involve your device's current or saved location being sampled periodically (as frequently as every fifteen minutes, including in some cases even if the Portal is not open/active on your device) and stored on your device, using GPS (where available), wireless tower, and Wi-Fi/WLAN hotspot information, and in some cases, as your device moves locations, your device’s location information will be sent to our servers so that we may associate such information to your user profile in order to customize your experience, and provide you with more relevant promotional or BBM Channels or Official Accounts content, including localized or time-sensitive offers that utilize geo-fencing functionality based on your device's current location. If you use Third Party Offerings which provide location-based services, please review the third party’s terms and conditions and privacy policy regarding how your location and Personal Information will be processed, and how to opt-out of any location-based services and advertising provided by the third party. You may manage through the settings on your device either the overall settings for your device’s GPS or location functionality or individual settings for the Services. 

  11. **Networks and connections**. CMW Group collect information about the people, Channels or Official Accounts, pages, accounts and groups you are connected to and how you interact with them on our Platform. CMW Group also collect contact information if you choose to upload, sync or import it from a device (such as an address book or call log or SMS log history), which CMW Group use for things like helping you and others find people you may know. 

  12. **Quality Assurance And Customer Service** : If you contact CMW Group for support, or send diagnostics or other technical information to us through email or logging tools provided by us for such purposes, you agree that CMW Group may collect technical information like device identifiers, hardware ID and model number, memory status, operating system and environment information, Wi-Fi/WLAN information, radio or wireless strength and connections, list of installed applications, application usage information, data regarding processes running and device configuration, and other information regarding the condition of your device and the software on your device that may be helpful for diagnostic purposes. Such information will be used for the purposes of troubleshooting, customer support, software updates, and improvement of CMW Group’s products and services in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You acknowledge and agree that your customer service telephone calls with CMW Group and its service providers may be recorded or monitored for quality assurance and customer service purposes such as to assist CMW Group in addressing your inquiries, troubleshooting, training and analytics to identify trends and make improvements to the Services. 

  13. **Third Party Information** : Portions of the Services may require or utilize Third Party Offerings to function. If you choose to integrate or link the Services with Third Party Offerings (for example, services that facilitate your use of the Services in association with social networking or other services offered by third parties), you authorize and consent to CMW Group’s use of your user account credentials and CMW Group’s Use of your Personal Information relating to such Third Party Offerings in order to facilitate your access to such Third Party Offerings for your personal and/or domestic purposes. Such information may include: (i) your account ID, password(s), authentication tokens, or other credentials for each such Third Party Offerings or other account(s) you integrate with the Services; (ii) your user account information (for example, account ID, display picture, display name, status update, availability status, country, time zone, unique device identifiers, etc.); (iii) on-device contacts information; (iv) an indication of which third party applications or services you have connected to your user account; and (v) session data resulting from your use of the third party applications or services you have connected to your user account (for example, high scores you have achieved in a connected third party game or application for display in your account profile box, instant messaging data resulting from instant messaging chats you have undertaken within a connected third party application or service and which have been facilitated by the Services' instant messaging functionality, etc.). You also authorize and consent to us obtaining Personal Information from and disclosing Personal Information to the applicable third party service providers (including your Internet service or mobile data service providers) for activation, billing, provision, service, maintenance, and deactivation purposes. Any Third Party Offerings accessed or used by you are not under CMW Group’s control. If necessary to fulfil CMW Group’ identified purposes, you consent that CMW Group may collect your Personal Information from third parties including your Internet service or mobile data service providers and combine such information with information you have submitted or otherwise made available to CMW Group. 

  14. **Information from partners**. CMW Group also receive information about your online and offline actions and purchases from third-party data providers who have the rights to provide us with your information. Partners receive your data when you visit or use their services or through third parties they work with. We require each of these partners to have lawful rights to collect, use and share your data before providing any data to CMW Group. 

Some of this information would not by itself identify you to CMW Group or be personally identifiable and is therefore considered non-Personal Information. If CMW Group combines any such non-Personal Information with other Personal Information available to CMW Group, the combined information will be treated as Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

* **HOW CMW GROUP USES YOUR INFORMATION**

CMW Group may use, collect, disclose and/or process your Personal Information, for the following purposes: 

  1. to provide the Services and/or Third-Party Offerings, _e.g._ : 

    1. for purposes related to the billing, activation, provision, maintenance, support, trouble shooting, resolving of disputes, deactivation, replacement, upgrade or update of the Services; 

    2. to better understand, analyse and predict user preferences and interests, and combine such information with other information to customize user experience; 

    3. to ensure the Services are technically functioning as intended and to help identify and troubleshoot issues; 

    4. to facilitate your access and use of Services and/or Third-Party Offerings; 

    5. to send invitations-to-subscribe, messages and posts within the Services on behalf of Channel or Official Accounts administrators; 

    6. to combine such information with information obtained from other sources (including Third Party Offerings) in connection with the provision of the Services; 

    7. to fulfil or enforce Notices applicable to the Services; 

    8. to manage or respond to your inquiries; 

  2. to develop new and enhance existing Services and to provide you with information on third party content or related products, services and software including to communicate with you about them using various means, e.g. to make available or send to you: 

    1. upgrades or updates, or notices of upgrades or updates, of the Services or third-party content or related products, services and software; 

    2. notices of promotions, contests, offers and upcoming events; 

    3. personalised information, surveys, marketing materials, advertisement or customised content; 

  3. to collect, use and disclose advertising identifiers, including those provided by other software platforms, or similar identifiers, to facilitate the CMW Group in conducting analytics or the provision of promotional content or other information that may be relevant to you; 

  4. to manage and develop CMW Group’s business and operations, e.g.: 

    1. to detect, monitor, investigate, mitigate or attempt to prevent fraud and technical or security issues or to protect the property of the CMW Group; 

    2. to allow for business continuity and disaster recovery operations; 

    3. to obtain legal services, to seek legal advice and/or to enforce CMW’s legal rights or the legal rights of any other member of the CMW Group; 

    4. for statistical purposes; 

  5. to meet legal and regulatory requirements and to respond to emergency situations, e.g.: 

    1. to respond to court orders, warrants or other lawful or enforcement requests or legal processes; 

    2. to provide emergency assistance in situations that may threaten the life or physical safety of you or others; or 

  6. for any other purposes for which you have consented, such as those that may be set out in Notices, and other purposes as permitted or required by any applicable laws and regulations. 

* **RETENTION, TRANSFERS, COMMUNICATION**

  1. **Retention**

CMW Group retains Personal Information as long as necessary for the fulfilment of the CMW Group’s identified legal and/or business purposes or as otherwise necessary to comply with applicable laws. When Personal Information is no longer necessary or relevant for such purposes, or upon any valid and lawful request from you or required by applicable laws, CMW Group will take steps to have it deleted, destroyed, erased, aggregated or made anonymous.

  2. **International operations and onward transfers**

You agree that, to be able to better serve you and facilitate the use or functioning of Services, your Personal Information may be collected, used, processed, transferred or stored by or on behalf of CMW Group in multiple jurisdictions including Canada, the United States, the European Economic Area, Singapore and any other country where CMW Group or their service providers have offices or facilities, including countries which may be outside the region in which you are situated and may have different privacy or data protection legislation, and may therefore be subject to the laws of these countries. If you are a resident of the European Economic Area or a country which restricts data transfers outside of that jurisdiction or region without your consent, you consent to your Personal Information being transferred outside of the European Economic Area or your country for processing or storage by or on behalf of CMW Group. 

Given the international nature of CMW Group’s business, the CMW Group may also be required to disclose or otherwise provide access to your communications data, including the contents of your communications, and other information under the laws of countries where CMW Group, their service providers and data are located. By using the Services, you consent to CMW Group’ compliance with applicable laws including any legal process that CMW Group believes requires them to produce or provide access to your communications data and other information. 

  3. **Marketing communications**

**CMW Group may communicate with you by a variety of means, such as using the telephone number(s) and/or email address(es) associated to your user account or your unique user identifier (e.g., BBM PIN or Custom PIN). CMW Group may communicate information, surveys, marketing materials, advertisements or customized content which has been personalized to try to make it more relevant to you as part of your relationship with CMW Group**. For example, we may do so where you have not unsubscribed from receiving such communications and it is permitted by law, where you have explicitly agreed to receive such communications, where you use free services which rely upon advertising (including targeted advertising based on profile information), or through utilizing aggregated data or data that has been made anonymous. CMW Group may ask you from time to time if you would like to receive from the CMW Group or authorized third parties selected by CMW Group, additional announcements, news, offers or event invitations regarding CMW Group and the Services. You may also choose to provide CMW Group with information in response to various promotional activities of CMW Group. If you agree to participate in contests, surveys, giveaways, reviews, or other promotions that CMW Group sponsors or co-sponsors, please ensure that you read the Notice that may be associated with these initiatives in order to obtain further details about how your Personal Information will be managed. Typically, an unsubscribe mechanism is included with every CMW Group marketing or commercial communication. Please visit the section below on “Managing your preferences” for more information on managing marketing or commercial communications from CMW Group. 

  4. **Service-related communications from CMW Group**

CMW Group may also send you certain service-related communications. For example, CMW Group may send a welcome email or message when you first register for your user account to inform you about the service and its terms, to notify you of important changes, to tell you how to manage your credentials or account, to provide service infrastructure notifications or information about upgrades or updates, safety or security information, or for surveys of current or former users. Because such service-related communications are important to your use of the Services, you may not opt-out of receiving these communications. 

  5. **Information sharing**

**General**. Except as outlined in this Privacy Policy, your information will never be sold to or shared with other companies or organizations for commercial purposes or otherwise. CMW Group may transfer Personal Information within our CMW Group and to sub-contractors that help us provide our Services. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our sub-contractors. Such sub-contractors may include third-party record or payment processors who process your credit card and other payment information for CMW Group but are otherwise not permitted to store, retain or use such information. CMW Group may also share information with CMW Group’s financial, insurance, legal, accounting or other advisors that provide professional services to the CMW Group. 

**Non-disclosure Agreements**. CMW Group uses contractual or other means to provide a comparable level of protection while the information is being processed by CMW Group’s service providers. It is CMW Group’s policy to enter into confidentiality obligations with any third party that obtains confidential information including Personal Information from CMW Group. For example, except where CMW Group is required or permitted by law to disclose Personal Information, CMW Group’s service providers to whom we provide your Personal Information typically agree to hold the information in confidence and only use the information for the purposes for which it was provided or to comply with applicable laws. 

**Third Party Offering**. If you purchase or use a Third Party Offering (e.g. paid content subscription service, downloaded application), CMW Group may share certain information with the third party for purposes of allowing us to provide you with great new third party products, services or software and your information may also be subject to the third party’s privacy policy. We encourage all CMW Group’s users to learn about the privacy practices of such third parties before agreeing to purchase or obtain their products, services or software. CMW Group does not directly control how such third parties process any Personal Information they collect in connection with the Third Party Offerings you use. In some cases, you may adjust the permissions granted to Third Party Offerings. You should periodically review these permissions including default permissions, as well as the Options or Settings menu on your device, in order to learn more about its security and available controls. If you wish to revoke the permissions granted to a Third Party Offering, please email us at [support@bbmtek.com](mailto:support@bbmtek.com). 

**Third Party Purchaser**. In the event of the sale of all or a portion of CMW Group’s assets, CMW Group may provide your Personal Information to the third party purchaser. You hereby consent to the Use of your Personal Information by CMW Group for the purposes of any purchase, sale, lease, merger or amalgamation or any other acquisition, disposal or financing of CMW Group or a portion of CMW Group or of any of the business or assets of CMW Group. 

**Advertisers**. CMW Group may utilize third parties (e.g., advertising networks) to provide advertisements using non-personally identifiable attributes or anonymised data that is derived from profile data processed by CMW Group, and provide such third parties with general statistics relating to the advertisements delivered. Please visit the section below on “ **Managing your Preferences** ” for more information on managing marketing or commercial communications from the CMW Group. 

* **ACCURACY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

CMW Group takes reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is sufficiently accurate, complete and up-to-date. CMW Group also depends on you to update or correct your Personal Information whenever necessary. You represent and warrant that all information provided by you is accurate and complete, and that none of it is misleading or out of date. You will promptly update CMW Group in the event of any change to the Personal Information provided or otherwise made available by you to CMW Group. Failure to do so may delay or prevent the provision of Services to you. 

* **SAFEGUARDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

CMW Group continues to review and implement physical, organizational and technological measures used to protect your Personal Information against loss or theft, unauthorized access, alteration or disclosure appropriate to its level of sensitivity. If there is any personal data breach, CMW Group will investigate and resolve the issue(s) as soon as possible, and where necessary, or required by specific laws, notify you and/or the relevant regulator(s). 

CMW Group seeks your cooperation to safeguard your Personal Information. You can reduce risk of unauthorized access to your Personal Information by using common sense security practices. For example, you are responsible for utilizing appropriate security measures to control access to your device and computer system, which includes creating a strong password that cannot be easily guessed by others (e.g. by including punctuation marks, numbers, capital and lowercase letters, and choosing a password of an appropriate length and which does not include your name or account name), using different passwords for different services, maintaining the confidentiality and security of your password and/or OTP code, not sharing access to your email or device, setting an adequate pass code to unlock your device, keeping your email and/or telephone number up-to-date, and using up-to-date antivirus software. Please note that CMW Group will never contact you to request your disclosure of your password or OTP code. 

* **ACCESS AND CORRECTION/RECTIFICATION REQUESTS AND INQUIRIES, LIMITING THE PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA**

Subject to any exceptions under Data Laws, you may request for access to and/or request correction/rectification of your Personal Information, request to limit any Use of your Personal Information and/or make any inquiries regarding your Personal Information, and/or only where permitted by applicable laws and regulations, request for the deletion/erasure of your Personal Information, by contacting: 

**CMW Group Data Protection Officer**

**(Copy: Legal & Regulatory) **

**238B Thomson Road,  
#17-05/08 Novena Square,  
Singapore 307685   
Email: [dpo@bbmtek.com](mailto:dpo@bbmtek.com) **

Upon written request, CMW Group will, within a reasonable timeframe, (i) provide you with access to your Personal Information; (ii) amend your Personal Information and notify any third parties as required by applicable laws; (iii) delete/erase your Personal Information in accordance with the applicable laws and regulations. 

Subject to any laws of your home nation or otherwise in the country, state and city in which you are present while using the Services, CMW Group reserves the right to impose a fee for access of your Personal Information in the amounts as permitted therein. 

In respect of your right to access and/or correct your Personal Information, CMW Group has the right to refuse your requests to access and/or make any correction/rectification to your Personal Information for the reasons permitted under law, such as where the expense of providing access to you is disproportionate to the risks to your or another person’s privacy. 

For example, CMW Group may not provide access to information if doing so: 

  1. would likely reveal Personal Information about a third party; 

  2. could reasonably be expected to threaten the life or safety of another individual; 

  3. would reveal CMW Group’s confidential commercial information that could harm the competitive position of CMW Group; or 

  4. includes information that is protected by legal privilege; or 

  5. includes information that was collected for the purposes of an investigation of a possible or actual breach of a contract, or contravention of a regulation or law. 

In order to safeguard your Personal Information from unauthorized access, CMW Group may ask that you provide sufficient information to identify yourself prior to providing access to your Personal Information. 

* **QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS?**

If you have any questions, regarding this Privacy Policy please contact CMW Group (and CMW Group’s Data Protection Officer) either by email or in writing and CMW Group will use commercially reasonable efforts to respond. 

  1. **Managing your preferences**

Generally, you may withdraw at any time your consent for CMW Group to collect, use, process and/or disclose your Personal Information or request us to limit the Use of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, subject to the Data Laws. However, please note that such requests may affect CMW Group’s ability to provide the Services to you. For example, although you can use the Services for some purposes without providing us with any Personal Information, CMW Group may need to process Personal Information for some services, including those that require payment or involve an ongoing relationship such as registration or subscription services. As such, if you refuse to provide CMW Group with the information it requires or later contact us in writing at one of the addresses above to withdraw your consent to use and disclose this information, CMW Group may no longer be able to provide you with your requested Services. In such event, we shall be entitled to treat such withdrawal as your termination of any agreement which you may have with us, without prejudice to any rights and remedies which we may have in law. 

**Marketing or commercial communications:** You may unsubscribe from receiving marketing or commercial communications about the Services by: 

    1. clicking the unsubscribe link at the end of any marketing or commercial communication from CMW Group; or 

    2. by writing to the CMW Group’s Data Protection Officer ([dpo@bbmtek.com](mailto:dpo@bbmtek.com)) and advising what particular types of marketing or commercial communications you no longer wish to receive. 

**Cookies** : As noted above, you may also opt-out of CMW Group’s use of Cookies by changing your browser settings to refuse Cookies or to indicate when a Cookie is being sent. 

  2. **CMW Group’s Ongoing Efforts to be Transparent**

CMW Group continues to make available information to help users better understand CMW Group’s Use of Personal Information and how to exercise choices regarding such Use through various channels including this Privacy Policy, applicable Notices and additional information that may be made available from time to time on the BBM website at: <https://www.bbm.com/en/>

  3. **Acknowledgment, Consent and Changes to this Privacy Policy**

CMW Group will occasionally update this Privacy Policy so that it remains relevant and current with changing technologies, applicable laws, CMW Group’s evolving business practices and the needs of CMW Group’s users. CMW Group encourages you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed of how CMW Group manages your Personal Information. If any changes are made to this Privacy Policy, CMW Group will revise the “Date of Last Revision” that is indicated on the Privacy Policy. 

If material changes are made to this Privacy Policy, we will notify users by placing a prominent notice at <https://www.bbm.com/en/legal/privacy-policy.html> or by other means, to provide you with the opportunity to review the changes. If you object to any changes, you my close your account and/or stop using and/or accessing the Services. Your continued use of CMW Group’s Services after notice of the change has been given, means that you have consented to the updated Privacy Policy.
